Maria Evangeline Aguirre, CPA Audit Manager, Ernst & Young LLP Contact Numbers: +65 9277 6745

E-mail address: maria.evangeline.aguirre@gmail.com



Executive Summary

Evangeline is a Certified Public Accountant with a cumulative experience of almost 11 years in both operations and audit roles, almost 10 years of which are from external audit with Ernst & Young. She is currently serving as a senior manager in Ernst & Young Singapore. Her clients were mainly from the financial services industry with focus on wealth and asset management companies (private equity funds, hedge funds and fund management companies). She has worked with the different offices of Ernst & Young from Manila, Philippines and Singapore. She was also sent by the Ernst & Young Singapore office for a secondment opportunity to audit a huge private equity funds group in the Ernst & Young New York office due to being a consistent high performer in the team.

Prior to joining Ernst & Young, she has also served as team leader in the operations department of a huge telecommunications company in the Philippines, handling more than 10 people in the team. She has been promoted to the team leader role in less than 1 year from being a staff in the said telecommunications company.

In her various roles, both in audit and in operations, Evangeline has consistently been commended by her superiors for her excellent work habits, valuable contributions to the firm/company and often selected for special engagements requiring special attention and technical competencies. She is also often assigned to manage complex audit engagements involving only high performing team members who can deliver both quality audits and exceptional client service. Evangeline's overall experience ranges from financial audit, financial analysis and reporting, compliance reporting requirements and operations management. She enjoys interacting with different people, an excellent manager, team player and is a diligent person with an eye for detail. She responds well in a high-pressure environment and values excellence in her career.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager

October 2016 – to present - Ernst & Young (Singapore)

Manager

October 2013 – September 2016 - Ernst & Young (Singapore)

Supervisor

October 2012 – September 2016 - Ernst & Young (Singapore)

Senior

July 2010 – September 2012 - Ernst & Young (Singapore) Assistant up to Senior

November 2006 to June 2010 – Ernst & Young (Manila)

Financial Audits

- Specialized in the financial audits of companies in the asset management industry, such as hedge funds, private equity funds and fund management companies;
- Proficient with Singapore Financial Reporting Standards (FRS), International FRS and United States Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (US GAAP);
- Reporting directly to audit partners including overall management of multiple audit engagements including planning, budgeting, staffing management, engagement economics and coordination with other Ernst & Young offices and internal Ernst & Young technical teams such as tax, valuation and compliance;
- · Managing engagement teams and ensuring that engagement metrics are met;
- Reviewing client's financial statements in detail for various reporting standards as well as relevant supports;
- Overseeing the review of annual income tax computations and other reports from the clients as required by regulatory bodies such as ACRA or IRAS and discussing financial reports, management letters, proposed audit adjustments and other reports with client's management;
- Reviewing investment valuation memos and supports provided by clients against independent sources or reviewing the basis for valuation methodologies for private equities (ie. discounted cash flows, peer multiple analysis, etc);
- Reviewing the results of the procedures performed by audit staff and audit seniors including team management and coordination;
- Evaluating staff and seniors' performance, determining the appropriate courses of action and preparing performance feedback and appraisals of staff and seniors.

WORK EXPERIENCE (cont'd)

Regulatory Reporting and Compliance

- Planning and conducting compliance review of regulated financial institutions with Capital Market Services (CMS) license, Registered Fund Management Companies (RFMC) license status. Reviewing clients' compliance with rules and regulations as prescribed under the Securities & Futures Act and related guidelines as prescribed by the MAS;
- She has participated in 2 rounds of MAS inspections (2011 and 2014) where Ernst & Young Singapore was selected to conduct inspections of CMS license holders including fund managers, corporate finance advisory firms, etc, to inspect the regulatory documents and ensure compliance with regulatory requirements ob behalf of MAS;
- She has engaged in numerous discussions with clients and inspectees in the asset management industry to provide recommendations on areas of gaps and also best practices for compliance and regulatory requirements in the financial services industries.

Others

- Selected for inter-office secondment to the Ernst & Young New York office to help out the engagement team there for the audit of a huge private equity fund group in New York;
- Involved in the area initiative to offshore work to Ernst & Young Philippines; selected to be trained in Ernst & Young Hong Kong to pilot the first batch of engagements to be offshored to Ernst & Young Philippines;
- Conducting technical training for local audit staffs;
- Selected to perform the audit of one of the most complex private equity funds in the team and successfully delivering key client deliverables;
- Selected for a special engagement amongst the asset management team to conduct multi-location audit of service organization controls and operating effectiveness under International Standard on Assurance Engagements 3402 for a global bank (sent to the client's offices in Mumbai, India; Hong Kong; and Manila, Philippines for at least 3 weeks on each location.

Operations Experience Prior to Audit

Ø January 2005 to January 2006: Team lead, ePLDT Ventus (Call Center Services)

CERTIFICATIONS TAKEN & PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION

October 2006 Certified Public Accountants (C.P.A.) Licensure Examination

Member, Philippine Institute of Certified Accountants (PICPA)

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

1999-2004 UNIVERSITY OF SANTO TOMAS

Bachelor of Science in Commerce, Major in Accountancy

REFERENCES Available upon request